VICTOR VÉLIZ

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with 8 years of experience in design, development and implementation of web applications, database modeling (SQL and NoSQL) and algorithm optimization. Oriented to Agile development. Expert in frontend (HTML, CCS, JavaScript) and backend (PHP, Python and JavaScript) technologies. Oriented to obtain knowledge in different technologies that allow me to optimize the logical development to ensure the functionality of applications and better user experience.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer - ISEI Empresa Inteligente

Sep 2023 - Present

- Update and develop PHP (Codeigniter), pure PHP, Javascript, Jquery, CSS, MariaDB and MongoDB databases.
- Maintain and generate documentation of applications and tests performed.
- Implement the use of Git version control and Docker development environments.

Web Project SGS Full Stack - Administración Enrique Duhau

Ene 2023 - May 2023

Design, develop and implement a support system that will manage requirements requests related to the
organization's various process control systems. In addition to managing and organizing resource
allocations and inventory of computer and communications equipment. Developed under the
Codeigniter, Jquery and Bootstrap frameworks. MySQL database. Git Version Control. Scrum
methodology.

Assistant Manager IT - Hato el Oso (Bufalinda)

May 2019 - Dic 2022

- Design, Develop and implement web applications for the different departments of the organization (Purchasing, Sales, Inventory and Finance) to ensure the documentation and process management required to comply with ISO-9001, BPM, SQF, HACCP standards.
- Be part of the organization's leadership team in development under Agile Methods, skrum and drive the methodology in the rest of the departments.
- Train personnel in technology tools required for their position.
- Maintain the operability and updating of the implemented systems.
- Lead the processes of improvement in systems, applications and technological equipment of the administrative and operational network of the organization.
- Manage customized application solutions to ensure compatibility with other internal systems of the organization from the ERP Microsoft Dynamics SL 2011 and 2014.
- Provided support in the different departments of the organization in the face of system failures, handling errors, connectivity problems, infrastructure and equipment support.
- Monitored and supervised the services provided on the servers of the organization in addition, perform the lifting and activation of services for failures or unforeseen drop.

- Develop a product serialization system by weight (fixed-variable), implementing the use of barcodes and QR. to later integrate it with the processes of invoicing, dispatch and returns with the ERP Microsoft Dynamics SL.
- Migrate the statistical system from an Excel file to a web application with real time connection to the Microsoft Dynamics SL ERP database, which showed related sales, production and return data by day, month and year.
- Develop web applications for the management of critical control processes in the purchasing, sales, quality, and AIT departments.
- Support installation and maintenance work of technological equipment, networks and telecommunications.
- Performed installation work, upgrades (software and Harware), maintenance and de-installation of computer equipment.

Web Developer - Adamantio C,A

Nov 2015 - Mar 2016

 Develop Web solutions (Web Pages, CRM Systems, ERP, Modular Systems) MySQL database management, design in CSS, HTML, JavaScript and PHP Frameworks, Bootstrap, jQuery according to requirements.

TRAINING

I**ngeniero en Sistemas** (System Engineer) Universidad de Oriente-Monagas-Venezuela Graduate-2024

SKILLS

Programming Languages: PHP, JavaScript, Python, C#, Visual Basic

Front-end: HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, Jquery

Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, Codeigniter, Laravel, Django, FastAPI

Databases: MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB, MSSQL, Oracle

Tools: Docker, GIT

Methodologies: Agile, Scrum

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Other Skills: Open to Suggestions, Emotional Intelligence, Enthusiastic, Organized, Consistent, Attention to Detail.
- Languages: Native Spanish, English (Intermediate-Advanced)
- **Certifications:** Front End Development Libraries, JavaScript Algorithms and Structures, Responsive Web Design, Back End Development and APIs.



Portafolio: https://victor-jvp.github.io/